

Priya Elza Jacob

Phone: 0091-9995532188

Email:

priya.elza.jacob@gmail.co

<u>m</u>

CAREER OBJECTIVE

Looking forward to be a part of an organization that will convert my potential into performance and recognition for hard work, honesty and sincerity and thereby contributing to the growth of the organization and myself.

PERSONAL PROFILE

I am a **B.Tech Graduate in Information Technology** having about 2 years of work experience both in India and in the U.A.E. I love to be a successful member of a team where I can contribute my knowledge and skills. I wish to contribute meaningfully to the growth and success of the organization by undertaking challenging assignments and delivering quality and timely results, using my professional knowledge and skills. I have the ability to work under pressure, adaptability to changing work environment and accepting challenges in a competitive environment. Good communication skills, openness to learning and believing in teamwork are some personal qualities I have.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Lamprell June 2014 - August 2014 **Energy**

Ltd

Temporary Staff (IT)

- Designed and developed a store management software (Primesoft) to track real time information for a departmental store.
- Forms were developed that provides for data entry and queries using Oracle Form Developer-a productive development environment for internet business applications.
- Modules developed for the project :
 - User Management
 - Supplier Management
 - Customer Management
 - Shop Management
 - Inventory Management

RESUME

- Data storage and manipulation was performed in Oracle SQL Developer -an Oracle database IDE.
- Using Oracle SQL developer, performed table creation, updating and manipulation, execution of queries, exported data into formats like XML, Excel, PDF, etc., debugging and testing.
- Oracle Report Builder was used to generate reports that allowed the organization to centralize report processing and to better manage reporting.
- Specific SQL statements were generated using query builder to obtain customized report data.
- Reports generated were exported to formats like PDF and Word.

TECOM Investments, Dubai, UAE March 2013

August 2011

KPMO Analyst (April 2012 - March 2013)

- Participated as well as led requirements gathering for key stakeholders at TECOM. Translated these requirements into a system interface for the management of team improvement plans (TIP-ACTS).
- Developed workflows, security schemes, permissions, notifications and dashboards in JIRA 4.2.2 for the WMS a custom built organization project management tool.
- Performed customization of workflows and dashboards as well as configured custom fields and screens.
- Empowered users by coordinating and providing training and hands-on worksessions on using the WMS.
- Assisted in the creation of dashboard views, filters and guery reports.
- Developed detailed manual to improve user understanding of system and answer FAOs.
- Coordinated and worked closely with Group IT to document and trouble shoot fixes to WMS.
- Performed research on portals and have added content to the PMO's portal page.
- Attended trainings and vendor presentations on SharePoint 2010 and SharePoint 2013.

Trainee Intern (August 2011 - March 2012)

- Received JIRA training and developed workflows for various areas within TECOM.
- Developed pages and site map for the KPMO portal page.
- Participated in requirements gathering sessions and strategy discussions for the Work Management System (WMS).

Sutherland Global Services, Kerala, India - April 2011

December 2010

RESUME

Technical Support Executive

- Worked for McAfee to support Customers in the management and prevention of hardware viruses.
- Successfully eliminated viruses, Trojans, spyware, rootkits and other malware from Customers' PC in allotted time period and adhering to SLA agreements.
- Effectively applied security updates to Customers; operating system and reduced the risk of re-infection.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

LANGUAGES:

Core Java, Oracle, ASP.NET, C#, CSS, JavaScript, JQuery, C/C++, HTML, PL/SQL, XML, SQL, MS Office (Excel, Word, Power Point, Access).

IDE:

Microsoft Visual Studio 2010/2012, Net Beans, Eclipse, Microsoft SQL Server, Oracle JDeveloper, Oracle Form Builder, Oracle Report Builder, Oracle SQL Developer.

ACADEMIC PROJECT

FINAL YEAR PROJECT: (Tamil Nadu College of Engineering)

Fast Query Point Movement Techniques for Large CBIR Systems

Performing target search in content based image retrieval systems to find a specific image using efficient query point movement methods. This approach enabled reaching any given target image with fewer iterations in the worst and average cases. A new index structure and query processing technique was proposed to improve retrieval effectiveness and efficiency. Intended targets could be retrieved even with poor selection of initial query points.

(Front end: Java 1.6 Back end: SQL Server 2000)

COURSES ATTENDED

- Diploma in Java Technologies (Java1.6, J2EE, JSP, Servlets & Oracle 9i database) from NIIT, Kochi, India.
- Certification Course in ASP.NET from G-TEC, Kochi, India.
- Microsoft SharePoint Foundation 2010 from New Horizons, Dubai.
- Microsoft Excel 2010 from New Horizons, Dubai.

EDUCATION

Tamil Nadu College of Engineering, Tamil Nadu, India.

Graduation: May 2010

B.Tech Information Technology

Our Own English High School, Dubai, U.A.E.

Graduation: April 2006

Central Board of Secondary Education (10th and 12th)

ADDITIONAL

RESUME

Personal Details	
Date of Birth	October 29, 1988
Gender	Female
Nationality	Indian
Marital Status	Single
Driving License	Indian driving license
Languages	Fluent in Malayalam, Hindi and
	English
Visa Status	Residence Visa

.